<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-07-19T06:55:14+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Building intelligent systems to shape a smarter world.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">I attend AWS Summit as a Machine Learning Engineer at Coretechs!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/aws/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I attend AWS Summit as a Machine Learning Engineer at Coretechs!" /><published>2024-06-23T18:01:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-06-23T18:01:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/aws</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/aws/"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I attended the AWS Summit, where I immersed myself in the latest AI advancements presented by leading experts. AWS continues to lead in cloud computing and AI, offering innovative solutions like AWS SageMaker that streamline the development and deployment of machine learning models.</p>

<p>The discussions were not only technical but also centered on ethical AI and operational optimization, reflecting AWS’s commitment to responsible innovation. Networking with diverse professionals showed how AI is transforming various industries, from healthcare to sustainability.</p>

<p>This summit has been an invaluable experience. It enhanced my understanding of AI’s potential and the crucial role of platforms like AWS in driving technological advancements.</p>

<div class="row justify-content-sm-center">
    <div class="col-sm-8 mt-3 mt-md-0">
        

<figure>
  <picture>
    <!-- Auto scaling with imagemagick -->
    <!--
      See https://www.debugbear.com/blog/responsive-images#w-descriptors-and-the-sizes-attribute and
      https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/HTML/Multimedia_and_embedding/Responsive_images for info on defining 'sizes' for responsive images
    -->
    
    <img src="/assets/img/aws/myself.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="example image" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />
  </picture>

  
</figure>

    </div>
    <div class="col-sm-4 mt-3 mt-md-0">
        

<figure>
  <picture>
    <!-- Auto scaling with imagemagick -->
    <!--
      See https://www.debugbear.com/blog/responsive-images#w-descriptors-and-the-sizes-attribute and
      https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Learn/HTML/Multimedia_and_embedding/Responsive_images for info on defining 'sizes' for responsive images
    -->
    
    <img src="/assets/img/aws/namecard.png" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="example image" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();" />
  </picture>

  
</figure>

    </div>
</div>
<div class="caption">
    The left photo shows an attendee badge for me from CoreTechs at the AWS Summit 2024 in Washington, DC. The right photo features me posing in front of a large "AWS" sign at the event.
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="conference" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My experience at the AWS Summit, engaging with AI and networking with industry professionals.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mathematical Modeling in the 2024 MCM</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/math/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mathematical Modeling in the 2024 MCM" /><published>2024-03-13T18:01:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-03-13T18:01:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/math</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/math/"><![CDATA[<p>In the 2024 Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM), we explored the dynamics of ecosystems with a focus on the sea lamprey (Petromyzon marinus). Our study aimed to investigate the relationship between local resource availability, sex ratio variations, and their ecological effects. Here, I will introduce the mathematical models we used and some of their key equations.</p>

<h3 id="aquatic-nutritional-network-ann-model">Aquatic Nutritional Network (ANN) Model</h3>

<p>The Aquatic Nutritional Network (ANN) model helps us understand how food resources influence the sex ratio in fish populations. This model includes factors like larval growth, algal reproduction, and the dynamics of small and large fish populations.</p>

<h4 id="key-equations-in-the-ann-model">Key Equations in the ANN Model</h4>

<p><strong>Larvae Population Dynamics:</strong>
\(\frac{dL}{dt} = \alpha_{m}\alpha_{f}N_{m}(t)N_{p}(t) + a_{l}A(t) - mL(t)\)
This equation describes the change in larvae population over time, considering growth contributions from male nutrients and algae consumption.</p>

<p>To solve for the equilibrium state where the change in larvae population over time is zero:
\(\frac{dL}{dt} = 0 \implies \alpha_{m}\alpha_{f}N_{m}(t)N_{p}(t) + a_{l}A(t) - mL(t) = 0\)
Solving for \(L(t)\):
\(L(t) = \frac{\alpha_{m}\alpha_{f}N_{m}(t)N_{p}(t) + a_{l}A(t)}{m}\)</p>

<p><strong>Algae Population Dynamics:</strong>
\(\frac{dA}{dt} = c_{l} - a_{l}A(t)\)
This equation models the growth rate of algae and its consumption by larvae.</p>

<p>To solve for the equilibrium state where the change in algae population over time is zero:
\(\frac{dA}{dt} = 0 \implies c_{l} - a_{l}A(t) = 0\)
Solving for (A(t)):
\(A(t) = \frac{c_{l}}{a_{l}}\)</p>

<p><strong>Small Fish Population Dynamics:</strong>
\(\frac{dF_s}{dt} = c_{s} - (a_{m} + a_{f})F_s(t) + e_{s}F_s(t)\)
This equation accounts for the intrinsic growth rate of small fish, parasitism by larvae, and the environmental loss factor affecting small fish.</p>

<p>To solve for the equilibrium state where the change in small fish population over time is zero:
\(\frac{dF_s}{dt} = 0 \implies c_{s} - (a_{m} + a_{f})F_s(t) + e_{s}F_s(t) = 0\)
Solving for \(F_s(t)\):
\(F_s(t) = \frac{c_{s}}{(a_{m} + a_{f}) - e_{s}}\)</p>

<p>By solving these equations, we can better understand the equilibrium states of various populations within the ecosystem. These insights are crucial for predicting how changes in environmental factors or population dynamics can affect the overall stability and health of the ecosystem.</p>

<h3 id="determining-equilibrium-points-for-the-ann-model">Determining Equilibrium Points for the ANN Model</h3>

<p>To find the equilibrium points of the ANN model, we follow a systematic approach. At equilibrium, the rate of change for each population is zero, meaning the populations remain constant over time.</p>

<h4 id="setting-up-the-equilibrium-system">Setting Up the Equilibrium System</h4>

<p>We transform the system’s differential equations into algebraic equations to find the equilibrium points. Each equation represents a balance within a specific ecological niche:</p>

\[\begin{align*}
\left\{
\begin{array}{l}
\alpha_{m}\alpha_{f}N_{m}(t)N_{p}(t) + a_{l}A(t) - mL(t) = 0, \\
c_{l} - a_{l}A(t) = 0, \\
c_{s} - (a_{m} + a_{f})F_s(t) + e_{s}F_s(t) = 0, \\
b_{m}N_{m}(t) + b_{f}N_{f}(t) - c_{f}F_b(t) + e_{b}F_b(t) = 0, \\
a_{m}F_s(t) + P(t)L(t) - b_{m}N_m(t) = 0, \\
a_{f}F_s(t) + (1 - P(t))L(t) - b_{f}N_f(t) = 0.
\end{array}
\right.
\end{align*}\]

<h4 id="application-of-constraints">Application of Constraints</h4>

<p>Biological systems are often constrained by ecological realities. Population sizes are generally within certain bounds, such as carrying capacities or resource limitations:</p>

\[0 \leq N_m, N_p, A, L, F_s, F_b \leq 1\]

<p>All variables are normalized to the interval [0,1], representing proportions of maximum possible population sizes.</p>

<h4 id="numerical-solution-of-the-equilibrium-system">Numerical Solution of the Equilibrium System</h4>

<p>By determining these equilibrium points, we gain critical insights into the sustainability and resilience of the ecosystem, with implications for species conservation and resource management strategies.</p>

<p>After applying this models, we can better understand the ecological impacts of sex ratio variations and resource availability, which is crucial for conservation efforts and maintaining ecological balance.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="math" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the use of mathematical models to understand ecosystem dynamics and sex ratio variations in sea lamprey populations as part of the 2024 Mathematical Contest in Modeling (MCM).]]></summary></entry></feed>